Guide to the Charlie Robison Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
Charlie Robison Accessions
1989-2014
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Robison, Charlie
UPWC.19121
4 Linear Feet
4 boxes
The archive of singer-songwriter, Charlie Robison spans 1989-2014. Included are song lyrics, photographs, flyers, posters, and scrapbooks. The bulk of the collection is comprised of the 8 scrapbooks dating from 1989-2002 that include numerous photographs, newspaper and magazine articles, and memorabilia. Of note is the circa 1992 photo album that includes childhood pictures of Robison with his mother and siblings, as well as many snapshots from early performances with Two Hoots and a Holler, and ticket stubs from concerts Robison attended
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charlie Robison, 2019
Biographical Note
Singer-songwriter Charlie Robison was born September 1, 1964, in Houston and raised on his family's ranch in Bandera, Texas. By age 15, Robison began writing his own material, and eventually performed in Austin bands Chaparral and Two Hoots and a Holler, as well as the Millionaire Playboys. Robison attended then-Southwest Texas State University and played football until an injury ended his career. He moved to Austin and made his solo debut in 1995 with "Bandera." "Life of the Party" followed in 1998. In 2000, he teamed up with his brother, Bruce, and fellow Texan, Jack Ingram, and released "Unleashed Live." "Step Right Up," his second studio album, was issued in spring 2001. "Good Times" (2004) "Beautiful Day"(2009) and "High Life" (2013) followed, as well as two live albums: "Live" (2003), and "Live at Billy Bob's Texas" (2013). In 2018, Robison retired from performing due to complications from surgery. He and ex-wife, Emily Erwin of The Chicks, have 3 children together.
Scope and Contents
The archive of singer-songwriter, Charlie Robison spans 1989-2014. Included are song lyrics, photographs, flyers, posters, and scrapbooks. The bulk of the collection is comprised of the 8 scrapbooks dating from 1989-2002 that include numerous photographs, newspaper and magazine articles, and memorabilia. Of note is the circa 1992 photo album that includes childhood pictures of Robison with his mother and siblings, as well as many snapshots from early performances with Two Hoots and a Holler, and ticket stubs from concerts Robison attended
Index Terms
Subjects
Music -- Texas; Alternative country music; Americana (Music); Country music; Musicians -- Texas
Document Types
Scrapbooks
Subjects (Persons)
Robison, Charlie; Robison, Bruce
- Lyrics: "Loving Country" (9 pp); "Rain" (2 pp); and 2 versions of "Life of the Party" (1 p each), undated (Box 3305, Folder 1)
- 2 flyers for Two Hoots and a Holler – one at the Ritz, the other at the Black Cat, undated (Box 3305, Folder 2)
- 1992 tour schedule for Charlie Robison and the Millionaire Playboys; 1998 receipt from Monterey Artists, Inc., 1992, 1998 (Box 3305, Folder 3)
- 1989 hang tag for the State Fair of Texas for Two Hoots and a Holler; 7 Backstage passes, undated (Box 3305, Folder 4)
- George Jones' guitar g-string; metal skull from American Snipers, undated (Box 3305, Folder 5)
- Charlie Robison press packet, newspaper clippings, loose scrapbook page, and a March 1995 edition of Music City Texas magazine, various dates (Box 3305, Folder 6)
- 12 Photographs of varying sizes – most of Robison performing; 1 publicity photo and 1 negative; and 8 digital printouts, undated (Box 3305, Folder 7)
- Framed photograph of Charlie Robison in uniform for Southwest Texas State University football (number 92), circa mid-1980s (Box 3305)
- Framed photograph of Bruce Robison, Charlie Robison, and Jack Ingram, Photograph by Lawson Little, 2001 (Box 3305)
- Photograph: Robison, unidentified man, and Robert Earl Keen [?] hunting, undated (Box 3306)
- Photograph: Robison playing guitar. Music Zone, Asheville, NC. Janet Crump, photographer, July 3, 2011 (Box 3306)
- Photograph: Robison playing guitar. C Dunn, photographer, undated (Box 3306)
- "2nd Annual Charlie Robison's Baybash & Redfish Round Up." Rockport Fulton with Kevin Fowler, Sean McConnell, Turnpike Troubadours, and Jesse Jennings (11" x 17" poster), July 3, 2011 (Box 3306)
- "Live in Acuña at the Corona Club" (11" x 17" poster), circa May 26, 2012 (Box 3306)
- Scrapbook. 20 pages, 12.5" x 12.5", 1989 (Box 3306)
  Description
  Contains 53 photographs of Robison performing with Two Hoots and a Holler, as well as at parties and hanging out with friends. Also included are 12 concert ticket stubs (Stevie Ray Vaughan, George Jones, Dwight Yoakum, Rodney Crowell, Stray Cats, Carl Perkins, and others). Other items of note include a dollar bill signed by Stevie Ray Vaughan; 2 flyers for Two Hoots and a Holler concerts; a set list for George Jones; and a contract for Two Hoots and a Holler performance at the State Fair of Texas, September 15, 1989.
- Photo album. 36 pages, 11" x 12", circa 1992 (Box 3306)
  The bulk of the album consists of snapshots (60) documenting concerts, the Grand Canyon, parties, and a wedding (possibly sister Robyn Ludwick). Other subjects include the Continental Club, Bruce Robison, and Kelly Willis. Of note among the photos are four childhood ones of Charlie with his mother, alone, and with siblings. Also included are 2 clippings about the Millionaire Playboys, an early band Robison performed with.
- Scrapbook. 20 pages, 12.5" x 13", 1998-1999 (Box 3307)
  Contains 13 photographs of Robison performing and numerous newspaper and magazine clippings.
- Scrapbook. 20 pages, 12.5" x 13", 1998-2002 (Box 3307)
  Contains 12 photographs and numerous newspaper and magazine clippings. Also included is a program from a 2002 "My Brother and Me" concert in Wharton, Texas, with Bruce Robison; a 2000 letter from M.J., co-owner of Gruene Hall, and a 2001 letter from Jeca Salas at 99.5 The Wolf. Also of note are 2 sets of handwritten song lyrics: "Life of the Party" (4 pages), and "Beautiful Day" (1 page).
- Scrapbook. 20 pages, 12.5" x 13", 1999-2001 (Box 3307)
  Contains 14 photographs of Robison – mostly performing, but some off stage, as well as 2 photos of brother Bruce. 24 newspaper and magazine clippings document concerts and tours including ones with wife Emily Robison, and Bruce. Of note is a 1999 brochure for Nørdens største Countryfestival in Norway.
- Scrapbook. 20 pages, 12.5" x 13", 2000-2002, 2009 (Box 3308)
  Contains 20 photographs of Robison performing solo and with brother Bruce, as well as numerous magazine and newspaper clippings. Also included is a 2009 email forward of a review of Robison's performance at a New York nightclub.
- Scrapbook. 20 pages, 12.5" x 13", 2000-2001 (Box 3308)
  Contains 16 photographs of Robison performing and with fans. The rest of the scrapbook is comprised of newspaper and magazine clippings about Robison, his wife Emily, and brother Bruce.
- Scrapbook. 10 pages, 12.5" x 13", 2002 (Box 3308)
  Majority of the scrapbook contains 48 snapshots documenting the "My Brother and Me" tour in January 2002 (with brother Bruce Robison), and April 2002 in Gruene Hall, and in May 2002 at the Lee County Fair. Scrapbook was compiled by Missy Schuelke and contains her captions.